Hi, this is Sean Hobson.
Right now we're talking about the man-to-man defense.
We're talking about the positioning of our defensive man as the ball moves around the perimeter.
Obviously, when they have the ball, we're on the ball with our defense.
Then as the ball moves one pass away, we changed into deny defense.
Then as the ball moved to the top, we talked about being in "help side".
The main thing is, we want this guy to pointing to the ball and his man.
What we want to talk about now is a little bit different style of help side.
That's when the ball actually swings all the way to the opposite side away from the side of your man.
A lot of people are concerned, "What happens to my guy?
What if my guy is still standing out there?"
Well right now, he's the farthest person away to getting the ball, we're not really concerned about that.
So what we want this defender to do, is to drop all the way, in fact we want him underneath the basket, splitting, his body should be splitting the middle of the floor, even over a little bit.
Because what's going to happen is, if this guy beats his man on the drive, the only person back to help is this guy right here on defense and he's going to have to come out and try to either take a charge or stop this guy's drive.
Now, you say, "But what about my man on the other side?"
Well, sometimes you get beat on that with the simple fact that if he has to close up here on the drive and his man comes in, then this guy could dish off.
You've just got to be a good enough defender that you could come out and play defense here and get back on here.
But the main thing is, we want to be in help side deep here and even if this guy skips the ball back, you're going to be able to recover.
So make sure when the ball is opposite your man that you get all the way into the half court.
You see how he's dropped low enough too that he could see ball and his man when he's looking up the court.
That's very very important to know where the ball and your man is in the man-to-man defense.